{
  "reference_number": "12381",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Why would the Climate Change Commission need to advise on a specific target if the Government had already set it's goal as net\n zero emissions by 2050? That doesn't make sense. Also 2050 is way too late to take action we need to act now!"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Net zero emissions goal should be across all greenhouse gases including methane and CO2."
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Except in the circumstances where we can go into minus emissions by developing systems and procedures that transform the\n negative gasses into positive and can be used in locked controlled systems that create energy e.g. https://www.youtube.com/watch?\n\n reload=9&v=MnWsUHIdtzs Check this site out for more inspiration https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2016/11/ink-diamonds-bricks-\n and-other-things-we-can-make-out-of-pollution/"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The Bill should require Governments to set out how it will achieve the emissions budgets, including transition pathways."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "Unless they are changes that get us to zero emissions targets quicker and do not include Carbon Trading."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "Unless these changes get us to zero emissions targets quicker and do not include Carbon Trading."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Supporting, rewarding, providing information and subsiding all New Zealand industries/companies to make and commit to targets.\n\nThese include the farming sector, tourism sector, energy sector and government itself. Encouraging individuals to partake and be\nactively involved in behavioural, attitudinal and cultural changes that enable us to reach these targets. Encourage the New Zealand\n\nMedia to support all the processes involved in making the required changes instead of ridiculing industries, individuals, local\ngovernment/councils and organisations that take or make steps towards the required changes."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "The Climate Change Commission should not just be an advisory committee but have mechanisms built in that hold Government to\naccount and The Climate Change Commission should be able to make decisions and set policy under its own authority at armâ€™s\n\nlength from Government."
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Do not go near NZ ETS at all. This is not the way forward but a way for government and big industry to buy their way out of meeting\nit's targets. It does not change the status quo but enables it. https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f3_CYdYDDpk I strongly disagree\n\nwith NZ ETS"
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I agree with so many of the points in the Zero Carbon Emissions bill and believe we can take this so much further by being global\nforerunners.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
